In this video, I'm going to cover a limitation of the Recursive Descent
在这段视频中，我将讲述递归下降的一个限制
Algorithm that I presented last time. Here's the grammar from our last
我上次介绍的算法。这是我们上一节的语法
presentation, and here's its implementation again, as a set of
演示文稿，下面再一次展示它的实现，作为一组
mutually recursive function that together, implement this simple recursive
相互递归函数，共同实现这个简单的递归
descent strategy. And now, let's think about what happens.
下降战略。现在，让我们来考虑一下会发生什么。
When we go to parse the input int, simplest possible input strength.
当我们解析输入int时，尽可能简单的输入强度。
Well, let's work through it. So remember, we start with the function
好吧，让我们把它解决掉。记住，我们从函数开始
that implements all the productions for the non-terminal e.
其实现非终端E的所有产生。
And so what we're going to do here, we're going to call e.
所以我们在这里要做的是，我们要称它为e。
And that will try calling E1. All right?
这将尝试呼叫E1。好的?
And what is E1 going to do? E1 is going to call T.
那么E1要做什么呢？E1将呼叫T。
Because, of course, the first production is E goes to T.
因为，当然，第一部作品是E去T。
So let's take a look at what T does. T is going to try out the production of
那么让我们来看看T是做什么的。我们打算试生产……
T1, all right? And what does T1 do?
T1，好吗？那么T1是做什么的呢？
Well, T1 recognizes an int. Okay, so that's good.
嗯，t1可以识别int。好的，这很好。
And it will match it and return, okay, and then E will return and we will
它会匹配它，然后返回，好的，然后E将返回，我们将
succeed in parsing. And I forgot to mention it, also the
解析成功。我忘了提了，还有
process, the input point will be moved across the int, and so when we're done
过程中，输入点将跨int移动，因此当我们完成时
you will return, and we will have succeeded in parsing the string int
您将返回，我们将成功解析字符串int
because E return true the production for E return true, and we consumed all of the
因为E返回TRUE，所以E的乘积返回TRUE，所以我们消耗了所有
input. All right?
输入。好的?
So now, let's consider a slightly more complicated example, okay?
现在，让我们考虑一个稍微复杂一点的例子，好吗？
So let's try the input string Int times int.
让我们尝试输入字符串Int乘以int。
All right? So again, we start with the production E.
好的?再一次，我们从制作E。
Okay? And the first thing we'll do, is we'll
好吧?我们要做的第一件事，就是
try the production E1. Same thing we did last time.
尝试生产E1。和我们上次做的一样。
E1 is going to call the function T. And T is going to try the first
E1将调用函数T，T将尝试第一个
production for T. Which, again, is the production int.
T的生产量，也就是生产量int。
Okay? And the input pointer, of course, is
好吧?当然，输入指针是
here, and then it will try to match that against an int.
这里，然后它将尝试将其与int匹配。
Okay? If I match the first token in the input
好吧?如果我匹配输入中的第一个令牌
stream against the, the terminal int. And it will succeed.
流，终端int。它会成功的。
Okay? So the input pointer will be moved over.
好吧?因此输入指针将被移动。
So T1 will return true. All right?
因此T1将返回TRUE。好的?
And as a result. This right hand side here of the function
结果就是。函数的右侧
T will also succeed, because T1 returns true, so T will return true.
T也会成功，因为T1返回TRUE，所以T将返回TRUE。
Okay? Therefore, E1 will return true and E, E1
好吧?因此，E1将返回TRUE，E，E1
returning true will cause E to return true.
返回TRUE将导致E返回TRUE。
And in fact that will be the end of the execution of the program will terminate.
实际上，这将是程序执行的结束，也将终止。
E will return true and the input player will only have advanced as far as int,
E将返回TRUE并且输入播放器将仅前进到INT，
and so we will reject the parse. This is actually, ends up getting
因此我们将拒绝解析。这实际上是，最终得到了
rejected. And the question of course is what
被拒绝了。当然问题是什么
happened? All right.
发生了什么？好的。
Why didn't we succeed in parsing this input?
为什么我们没有成功解析此输入呢？
Which is clearly in the language of this grammar.
这显然是在这个语法的语言中。
Well, the story here is actually a little bit interesting.
嗯，这里的故事其实有点有趣。
What happened is down here when we discovered that Int matched the first
当我们发现Int与第一个
production for T, we said that T was done.
为T生产，我们说T做完了。
Okay, T had succeeded, had matched it's input.
好的，T成功了，匹配了它的输入。
And then, when E ultimately returns and the whole parse fails, because we haven't
然后，当E最终返回并且整个解析失败时，因为我们没有
consumed the input, we don't have a way to back track and try another alternative
消耗了输入，我们没有办法回溯并尝试另一个替代方案
for T. If we were going to succeed we would have
对于T来说，如果我们要成功，我们会有
to say, oh, well even though, we found a production for T that matched part of the
要说，哦，好吧，即使我们找到了T的一部作品，它与部分
input. Since the overall parts fail, that must
输入。既然整个部件都失效了，那肯定是
not have been the right production to choose for T.
不是为T选择的合适的制作。
Maybe we should try some other productions for T.
也许我们应该为T尝试一些其他的作品。
And in fact if we'd tried the second production for T, T2.
事实上，如果我们尝试了T，T2的第二次生产。
We would have matched Int times T, and then we probably would of succeeded.
我们会匹配Int乘以T，然后我们可能会成功。
We would have been able to manage int times int.
我们就可以处理int乘以。
Okay? And so, the problem here is that even
好吧?所以，这里的问题是，即使是
though there is backtracking within a production; while we're trying to find a
虽然在一部作品中有回溯；当我们试图找到一个
production that works for a given non-terminals.
为给定的非终端工作的产品。
So, while there is backtracking For a non-terminal during the time that we're
所以，虽然在我们的时间里有非终结点的回溯
trying to find a production that works for that non-terminal, but there is no
试图找到适用于该非终端的产品，但没有
backtracking once we have found a production that succeeds for
回溯一旦我们找到了一部成功用于
non-terminals. So once a non-terminal commits and
非终端。因此，一旦非终端提交并
returns and says, I have found a way to parse part of the input using one of my
返回并说，我已经找到了一种方法来解析部分输入，使用我的
productions. There's no way, in this particular
制作。在这种特殊的情况下，是不可能的
structure, this particular algorithm, to go back and revisit that decision and try
结构，该特定算法，以返回并重新访问该决策并尝试
a different production. All right?
一部不同的作品。好的?
So the problem is that if a production for non-terminal x succeeds, there's no
所以问题是，如果非终端x的生成成功，就没有
way to backtrack to try a different production for x later.
回溯到稍后尝试x的不同生产的方式。
So once x, once the function for x has returned.
所以一旦x，一旦x的函数返回。
And we're really committed to that production.
我们真的致力于这部电影的制作。
Now that means that the particularly Recursive Descent Algorithm that I showed
这意味着我展示的特别递归下降算法
in the last video, is not completely general, and Recursive Descent is a
在上一个视频中，不是完全通用的，而递归下降是一个
general technique. There are algorithms for Resursive
一般技术。对于Resursive，有一些算法
Descent parsing that can parse any grammar.
可以分析任何语法的下降语法分析。
That can implement the full language of any grammar.
可以实现任何语法的完整语言。
And they have more sophisticated backtracking, than what I showed in the
他们有更复杂的回溯，比我在
algorithm that I presented last time. Now the reason for showing this
我上次介绍的算法。现在展示这个的原因是
particular algorithm is that it's easy to implement by hand.
特殊的算法是很容易手工实现的。
So this is actually an algorithm, or approach to Recursive Descent that while
所以这实际上是一种算法，或者说是递归下降的方法
it has this limitation, as you can see, it's very mechanical and very
它有这样的限制，正如你所看到的，它非常机械，非常
straightforward to design a parser for a given for a given grammar.
为给定语法设计给定解析器的简单方法。
And it will work for a rather large class, class of grammar.
而且它适用于一个相当大的班级，语法班级。
So in particular, it'll work for any grammar where for any non-terminal at
因此，它特别适用于任何语法，其中任何非终结符都适用于
most one production can succeed. So if you know from the way that you've
大多数一部作品都能取得成功。所以如果你从你所知道的方式中知道
built your grammar, that in any situation, that the grammar can get into
建立你的语法，在任何情况下，语法都可以进入
or the Recursive Descent Algorithm can get into during parsing, that at most one
或者递归下降算法在解析过程中可以进入，最多只有一个
production can succeed. Then it this, this parsing is gradually
生产是可以成功的。那么它这个这个解析是逐渐的
will be sufficient, because there will never be, once you find a production that
将是足够的，因为一旦你找到一部作品，就永远不会有
succeeds, there will never be a need to go back and revisit that decision,
如果成功了，就再也不需要回去重新审视这个决定了，
because it must be the case that none of the other productions could have
因为这肯定是其他任何一部作品都不可能有的情况
succeeded. And it turns out that the example grammar
成功了。事实证明，示例语法
that we're working with in the last couple of videos could actually be
我们在最后几个视频中使用的东西实际上可能是
written to work with this algorithm. All right.
为使用此算法编写的。好的。
And we would have to left factor the grammar.
而且我们还得把语法因素留下来。
Well, actually there's more than one way to rewrite the grammar to work with this
实际上，有不止一种方法可以重写语法来处理这个问题
Recursive Decent Algorithm but one way to do it Is to left factor it.
递归的得体算法，但有一种方法是左因式。
I'm not going to say any more about left factoring in this video, because that's
我不会在这段视频中更多地谈到左因式分解，因为这是
going to be a topic of a video that's coming up shortly.
很快就会成为一段视频的主题。